# JHON DEIBER DIAZ PARRA

Montréal QC, Canada | (514)3461672 | jhondeiberd@gmail.com Portfolio | Linkedin | Github

**English** - Professional working proficiency French - Elementary proficiency

**Spanish** - Native or bilingual proficiency

# JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

### **ABOUT ME**

I am a creative person in problem solving and analytical thinking. During my studies, I have learned different technologies and programming languages, I am passionate about learning, teamwork and I want to get a great experience as a programmer and thus be able to contribute to the needs of companies and their customers. Throughout my career, I have been involved in large-scale complex projects, reengineering of functionalities and interfaces. I believe that innovation and continuous improvement is a success factors for organizations, so I tirelessly insist on applying these criteria in every initiative in which I have participated.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Web: HTML5, CSS3, Node.js, React, Web services API

Programming languages: Java, Python, GO, C#, C++, PHP, JavaScript, Transact-SQL

Mobile technologies: Kotlin, Flutter Control version: Git, GitHub, Bitbucket,

Project management: Scrum, Kamban, Trello, Planner Database: SQL server, MySql, MariaBD, PostgreSQL

Business Management Software: ERP Microsoft Dynamics, WMS Arcante, PLM Porini, ICG POS

### **PROJECTS**

**Application personal Budget Android** 

**Enviroment:** Kottlin – Android Associated with: ISI College

Code

Application developed in Kottlin - Android to manage income, expenses, and personal balance. Allows additional, edit, delete transactions, and is multilingual.

Application full-stack Manager favorite music albums

**Enviroment:** Node.js - ReactJs - PostgreSQL

Associated with: ISI College

Team users: Anuj Narang - Jhon Diaz

Code

Development of a web application for the user to manage a list of favorites, searching, adding, and deleting. It was built with a Back-end server using Node.js + Express for the REST APIs that manage the PostgreSQL database. The Front-end server is a React.js that request the user requirements with RESTful APIs for the Discogs Music. My role in this project was developing the Back-end part.

**MVC** application for managing contacts

**Enviroment:** C#

Associated with: ISI College

Team users: Ricardo Castano - Jhon Diaz

Code

Application developed in C# for contact management, a graphical interface that allows you to create new contacts, edit existing ones and delete them, these data are stored in text files. In this project worked. In this project, we worked on distributing parts of the menu for the project. In this project, we distributed parts of the menu for the project, and each

one coded and tested his part.

Administrador de la base de datos ERP

**Enviroment:** SQL server Associated with: ISI College I Developed and programed in Transact-SQL to rebuild and reorganize indexes and update statistics, backups to maintain optimal performance of the company's ERP database.

#### **TRAINING**

Programming and Web Technologies, Attestation of College Studies Institut Supérieur d'Informatique – Montreal, Canada	2021 - Present
Production engineer, Bachelor's Degree Universidad Distrital Francisco José de Caldas, Bogotá - Colombia	2008 - 2013
Industrial technology, Diploma of Vocational Studies Fundación Cidca, Bogotá - Colombia	2002 - 2005
CERTIFICATIONS	
Analyzing data with Power BI, Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate (MCSA) Lourtec IT Services and IT Consulting – Remote	2020 - 2020
<b>SQL 2016 Database Development</b> , Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate (MCSA Lourtec IT Services and IT Consulting – Remote	3) 2019 - 2020
<b>Developing C# - ASP.NET Core MVC</b> , Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate (MCSA) 2019 -2019 Lourtec IT Services and IT Consulting – Remote	
Object-oriented programming paradigm Fundación Carlos Slim– Remote	2021 - 2021
Database Administrator (DBA) Fundación Carlos Slim– Remote	2017 - 2018

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

# **Applications Manager ERP**

2017 - 2020

Permoda, Bogotá - Colombia

- Implemented agile methodologies for the execution and follow-up of projects and developments in Dynamics ERP.
- Supported my team with debugging code in the Dynamics ERP AOT for bug fixes.
- Developed database queries for incident resolution and analysis.
- Collaborated with product managers and third parties to identify and resolve issues coordinated system requirements, and created project schedules.
- Planned and executed annual budget for ERP improvement.
- Planned, implemented and supervised IT technology solutions to ensure satisfactory fulfillment of end-user requirements, implementation and support in a productive environment.
- Coordinated the development of virtual training material for the users' application

#### OTHER PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

Landscaper 2021 – Present

Boardwalk, Montréal QC, Canada

- Responsible for painting common areas of assigned buildings.
- Responsible for mowing the lawns around the buildings.
- Support the maintenance and concierges teams when necessary.

# **Applications Professional ERP**

2008 - 2017

Permoda, Bogotá - Colombia

- Escalated problems to the Technical Specialist Level III's or above within the support structure.
- Led the definition and formation of plans for applications aimed to master users' knowledge.

- Performed test runs for approval and implementation of developments in a production environment.
- Enhanced and maintained ERP functionalities and execute upcoming projects.
- Implemented and deployed ERP's standard modules and local functionalities.
- · Optimized processes and procedures in the ERP
- Developed virtual training material amended to extend the ERP modules.

## **Production Planning Analyst**

2006 - 2008

Permoda, Bogotá - Colombia

- Implemented Material Requirements Planning (MRP) methodology for product production
- Designed and configured technical sheets and spreadsheets for clothing products.
- Calculated the manufacturing route and the cost of the bill of materials for the garments.
- Applied engineering industrialization methods and plans to improve the manufacturing process to optimize operating costs.
- Optimized raw material inventories and allocation based on collection designs.

## **Production Engineering Analyst**

2003 - 2006

Permoda, Bogotá - Colombia

- Designed and enhance workload balancing for production plants.
- Implemented engineering methods and time analysis for the plans' workstations.
- Prepared operational listings for garments products.
- Designed and implement standards time for garments operations.
- Identified and improved bottlenecks for production modules.
- Prepared efficiency reports and control the unproductive time of the plant.